(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E22 -= Extra.Lap =- Subripped by zerox
麦姬，鲍勃叔叔怎么睡在我的办公室里？
Maggie, what's Uncle Bob doing sleeping in my office?
昨晚他和麦克打扑克
He and Mike played poker last night.
-麦克把房间赢回来了 -真的？
- Mike won his room back. - Really?
麦克总算占了点上风，我太高兴了
I'm glad to see Mike getting the upper hand for a change.
我也很高兴，不过他把你的车输了
Me, too. Too bad he lost your car.
说不定鲍勃叔叔能让我们 搭便车去商店呢
Maybe Uncle Bob wouldn't mind giving us a lift to the store later.
鲍勃叔叔呢？
Where's Uncle Bob?
-还在睡觉吧 -还没醒？
- Still asleep, I guess. - You mean, he's not up yet?
谢天谢地，爸，能借你的刮胡膏吗？
Thank you, God. Dad, can I borrow some of your shaving cream?
还要一段时间呢
I'd give it a while.
今天真是千载难逢
Come on, Mom. I may never get another chance like this again.
他一连4天早上都给我喷这个
He's sprayed me four mornings in a row.
一连4天早上？
Four mornings in a row?
-不留活口 -是，长官
- Take no prisoners. - Yes, sir.
-你真坏 -要拥护自己人嘛
- You're bad. - Always support the home team.
我和本赌10块钱，鲍勃会打败麦克
Ben and I have $10 saying Uncle Bob beats Mike in the limbo contest.
你们赌吗？
Want a piece of the action?
你们不难为情吗？
You two ought to be ashamed of yourselves...
打赌自己哥哥会输
betting against your own brother.
妈妈说得对
Your mother's right, kids.
这是麦克的主意，赢了他给钱
But it was Mike's idea. I mean, he said he'd cover any bet against him.
-而且是1赔3 -1赔3，哇
- And he's giving 3-to-1 odds. - 3-to1, whoa.
-杰森 -只是痒痒了
- Jason. - I'm just scratching.
麦克？
Mike?
他死了
He's dead.
我的天
Oh, my God.
我只想说在丧礼上哭泣.
For those of you that cried at the funeral...
并不是丢脸的事
I just want to say that it's nothing to be ashamed of.
谢谢，麦姬
Thank you, Maggie.
准备好了吗？
Well, are we all ready?
-感觉很不舒服 -开始后就会习来惯了
- This feels kind of strange, Mom. - It won't after we get started, honey.
这是鲍勃叔叔的纪念仪式
Uncle Bob called this a remembering session.
每当有家人去世.
When someone in my family passed on...
鲍勃叔叔就会引领我们去追思
Uncle Bob would lead us all in sharing fond memories of that person.
而且称之为“亲爱的死家伙”
Whom he would lovingly refer to as "The dearly defunct."
谁要开始？
Who wants to start?
好吧，我来
Okay, then, I will.
我小时候.
When I was a little girl...
想成为舞蹈家
I wanted to be a dancer.
知道为什么吗？
And do you know why?
为什么？
Why?
因为鲍勃叔叔带我去看了第一场芭蕾
Because Uncle Bob took me to my very first ballet.
记得他说过“她们用脚尖走路..”
And I remember he said, "They walk around on their toes...
“而且挥舞臂膀，这些动作很不合理”
"they do flapping things with their arms, and it doesn't make any sense.
“但是很美，对吗？”
"But it's pretty, ain't it?"
记得我割掉盲肠后.
Remember when I had my appendix taken out...
鲍勃叔叔用瓶子装了起来
and Uncle Bob brought me one in a jar and told me not to worry...
他说知道怎么放回去
'cause he knew how to put it back in.
护士过来了，他就拿出瓶子.
Yeah, and when the nurse came, he showed her the jar...
说是汽水贩卖机上出来的
and said he got it out of the soda machine.
而且他要退款
And then he said he wanted his quarter back.
还记得他超车时的动作吗？
And remember what to do when passing slow cars on the road?
划.
Stroke.
我记得最有趣的是.
I remember how much fun it was...
鲍勃叔叔总让麦克出糗
when Uncle Bob would make Mike lose.
什么？
What?
他跑得比你快，投篮比你准 扑克总是赢你
He could run faster, shoot baskets better. He played games like a champ.
-是我让他的 -是吗？
- I let him win. - Sure you did.
记得上次他来吗？
Remember the last visit?
最后冲刺，两人相差甚远
They're in the homestretch and it's not even close.
杰森，他又输了，他肯定伤心死了
Jason, he lost again. He'll be crushed.
我知道，他尽了全力
I know. He tries so hard, too.
他来了
Here he comes.
-谁跑第一了？ -鲍勃叔叔遥遥领先
- And the winner is? - Uncle Bob by a mile.
鲍勃叔叔!
Uncle Bob! Uncle Bob!
B-O-B. Uncle Bob!
好了，好了，纸币扔过来
Please, please. Just throw paper money.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
今天耍够了我儿子没有？
Are you through humiliating my son for the evening?
-不好说，凯罗？ -还来得及
- I don't know. Carol? - We can make it if we hurry.
来吧
Let's do it.
于是另一个人说.
So the other fellow says:
“如果我能那样走路，就不需要爽身粉了”
"If I could walk that way, I wouldn't need talcum powder."
还好你不是那个擦爽身粉的人
At least you're not the kind of guy who likes to rub it in.
谢谢你们合作
Thanks for the help, guys.
开玩笑，我们就喜欢这样
Are you kidding? We live for stuff like this.
-儿子，别让他们取笑 -我还受得了
- Don't let them tease you, Son. - That's all right, Dad. I can take it.
好样的，要比萨饼吗？
Attaboy. You want some pizza?
鲍勃叔叔中途买了一份
Uncle Bob stopped for one on the way back.
算了，别气馁，我最喜欢的外甥是你
Come on, pal. Don't take it so hard. You know you're my favorite nephew.
-你叫什么来着？ -这次让你赢了
- What's your name again? - All right, look, you beat me again...
但我还年轻，迟早会胜过你
but I'm young, and sooner or later I'm going to come out on top.
他还想受罪，明早再比
Glutton for punishment. Shall we say running shoes at dawn?
-好的 -好吧
- You're on. - All right.
看谁先到浴室
I'm first in the shower.
这回怎样？
How about that.
麦克总算赢你了
Mike finally got the best of you at something.
不见得，水龙头被我拿走了
Not really. I took the knobs off the shower.
我当时不是要淋浴
I didn't want to take a shower.
麦克，你能回忆起什么？
Your turn, Mike. What do you remember?
2，J，K，一对7
Deuces, jacks, man with an ax. Pair of natural sevens takes all.
扑克？
That's poker.
我喜欢跟鲍勃叔叔打扑克 尽管老是输
I loved to play poker with Uncle Bob, even if he did always win.
她是一位美丽的姑娘
Boy, she was some beautiful dame.
还以为能天长地久 战争爆发了，她就逃了
I thought we'd always be together. Then the war came. She shipped out.
我送了她一条香烟，到你了
I gave her a carton of cigarettes. Your bet.
如斯悲壮，你的爱情人生
Yeah, that's some sad story. I mean, the love of your life.
-后来又遇到谁了？ -都比不上她，一对J
- Didn't you ever meet anyone else? - No one like her. Two jacks.
爱是永不枯竭的
We'll always have Milwaukee.
鲍勃叔叔.
Hey, Uncle Bob...
我心仪几何课上的一位女同学
there's this girl in my geometry class that I like.
-每次看到她，我都会打颤 -就多穿点
- When I look at her, I get the chills. - Put a jacket on.
你几何才60多分，同志仍需努力
You got a D in geometry. Now, you can do better than that, you hear?
-我正在努力了
-1 - I know. I'm trying. - One.
-再努力点 -我会的
- Try harder. - I will.
我押10块
I bet $10.
我接受，加注10块
All right, I'll see your $10, and I'll raise $10 more.
-好，什么牌？ -三条1
- Call. What have you got? - I got three aces.
满堂红，三条9，一对4
Full house, nines and fours.
怎么老是你赢
I can't believe it, you win every hand.
小麦克，我年纪是你的4倍，我有经验
Mikey, Mikey, I'm four times older than you. I've got experience.
你也会有经验的，但我不会让你追上
One day you'll have experience, though I wouldn't hold my breath.
天哪!看看时间
Holy mackerel! Would you look at the time?
玩得这么晚，你妈妈会宰了我
Your mother's going to kill me for keeping you up this late.
没关系
Oh, no, that's okay. Really.
兴你有关的事，她都会从宽处理
She lets me get away with everything when it comes to you.
是吗？那么我们到城里弄个刺青
She does? Let's go downtown and get some tattoos.
-刺青？ -开玩笑的
- You got tattooed? - He was just kidding.
我从鲍勃叔叔身上学到最重要的是.
The most important thing I ever learned from Uncle Bob...
做人要口是心非
was just never draw to an inside straight.
记得那次感来恩节.
Hey, you remember that Thanksgiving...
鲍勃叔叔把整只火鸡.
when Uncle Bob brought the whole turkey out...
推到多丽思老姑妈面前
and he put it in front of big, old Aunt Doris?
他说“你先吃，我们的火鸡马上就来了”
And he said, "You go ahead and start. Ours will be out in a minute."
凌晨3点半把我弄醒
All right, already. Look, you wake me up at 3:30 in the morning.
我也算了
I say, "No problem."
我下去给你弄点吃的吧
I come down here and what do I get for you?
全脂牛奶
Buttermilk.
我最讨厌全脂牛奶了
That's right, buttermilk. I hate buttermilk.
不过我这下要喝了
But I'm going to drink some right now. You know why?
因为你喜欢
Because you like it. That's right.
够朋友了吧？
There, am I your buddy or what?
当然了
You betcha.
早上好
Morning, Mike.
做梦而已，不是真的
It was just a dream. It didn't really happen.
我的床，我爱你 谢谢你把它变成一个梦
My bed, I love you. Thank you for making it only a dream.
还有我的枕头
And my pillow.
我爱你枕头
I love you, pillow.
早餐好了
Breakfast is ready.
听我解释
I can explain all this.
不必了
Don't bother, Mike.
你和枕头之间的事，我们早就知道了
We've known about you and your pillow for a long time now.
她不会懂的
She just doesn't understand.
对不起，起床晚了
Sorry, I'm late, guys.
昨夜做了个怪梦
I just had this really weird nightmare last night.
大考结束前1分钟.
Is that the one where you show up for your final exam...
你才进入考场？
with less than a minute to go?
但这是真人真事
No, that actually happened.
昨晚的梦是荒唐的 醒过来我还真高兴呢
But it was just as crazy. I mean, I was pretty glad when I woke up.
我同意
I'll say.
现在大家都来了.
Well, now that we're all here...
是谁昨晚把牛奶撒了一地？
does anyone want to tell me who spilled buttermilk on the floor?
你招认就是了
A simple confession will do.
-没事吧？ -没事
- Are you all right, Mike? - Yeah.
-怎么了？ -没什么
- What happened? - Nothing.
有块东西跑错了管道
Something just went down the wrong pipe.
这下麻烦了
I'm in big trouble.
猜字游戏迷们，赛事愈发激烈了
And the tension's really building here, charade fans.
女士们领先，但麦克.西弗要追上了
The girls are ahead, and Mike Seaver's coming up for his next turn.
麦克，都半夜了 今晚就到此为止吧？
It's almost midnight, Mike. Can't we just call it a night?
正玩得开心呢
What, and end all the fun?
-我累了 -我也是
- I'm tired. - Me, too.
别这样，好，再来猜
Come on. Okay, here we go, Dad.
电影名，三个字，第一个字
It's a movie. Three words. First word.
怪.
Sounds like a monster.
开车怪
A monster with a car.
又是？
Oh, no, not another Godzilla movie.
的第二个字是？
Ben, what's the second word in every Godzilla movie?
-斯 -对
- Meets. - Right.
哥斯拉大战玛格丽特
Godzilla meets... Margaret Thatcher.
我提示一个， 我睡了
I'll give you a hint. It's Frankenstein. I'm going to bed.
-我也睡了 -谢天谢地
- Me, too. Let's go up. - Thank God.
等等，等等
Hey, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
玩大富翁吗？
How about a game of Monopoly?
这种游戏老少皆宜
Now, there's a game that's just fun for all ages.
麦克，刚玩过了
Mike, we've played Monopoly.
拼字游戏，巴棋戏，跳棋
And we've played Scrabble, Parcheesi, and ball tag.
一个晚上不能玩太多的游戏
I mean, there's a limit to how much fun a family can stand in one night.
两小时以前就不行了
And we passed it about two hours ago.
睡觉吧？
Coming, Mike?
我打个电话，看谁还在
No, I think I'll get on the horn and see who's around.
半夜三更打电话？
At midnight?
-再玩一把益智游戏好吗？ -好吧
- How about a quick game of Uncle Wiggly? - All right.
答错了
Wrong.
麦克，晚安
Night, Mike.
-你没事吧？ -没事，太兴奋罢了
- Mike, you okay? - Yeah, fine, great. Just feeling wonderful.
有什么话要说吗？
Sure you don't want to talk about it for a minute?
没什么，真的
No, there's really nothing to talk about, Dad. Really.
好吧，晚安
Okay. Good night.
爸爸，人死后会怎样？
Dad, what happens to people when they die?
这话说起来就长了
This could take longer than a minute.
谈一个晚上也可以
If it takes all night, it's okay by me.
好吧
Okay.
有人认为人死后会进天堂地狱
Some people believe that when you die, you go to heaven or hell.
有人认为.
Some people believe that...
人死后会轮回转世
then you come back again to live on earth...
来世的处境.
and the kind of life you have then...
要看前世
will depend on the kind of person you were.
也有人认为人回轮回.
Some people believe that you keep coming back...
来世会不断改善，直到顶点
in a higher form each time until you reach the ultimate.
当上职业篮球员？
Professional basketball player?
也许吧
Could be.
若是前世作恶，今世就会当律师
If you're not good, you come back as a lawyer.
喜欢恶作剧的人呢？
Where do practical-joking joggers fit in?
功德也算高的
Hopefully pretty high.
-爸爸，我见到他了 -谁？
- Dad, I saw him. - You saw who?
鲍勃叔叔
Uncle Bob.
昨晚我下来喝牛奶.
Last night I was drinking buttermilk...
他走过厨房，活生生的
and he ran through the kitchen, just like he was alive.
你是做梦吧
Maybe you were dreaming.
-牛奶都撒地上了，记得吗？ -记得
- Dad, the buttermilk spilled, remember? - Yeah.
是不是我疯了？
Was it possible, or am I just losing my mind?
也许是梦游，你的想象力.
You could have been sleepwalking, Mike. You know, the imagination is...
我知道你会这么说
I knew you would say that.
你相信有鬼吗？
Dad, do you believe in ghosts?
-我.. -你不信吧
- Well... - I didn't think so.
我相信你相信看到鲍勃叔叔了
I believe that you believe that you saw Uncle Bob.
真的，他要我干什么？
I did. Dad, what does he want from me?
他说了些什么？
What did he say?
他说“早上好”
He said, "Hi, Mike."
很友好
Sounds pretty friendly.
我不知道怎么办，他还会回来的
Dad, I don't know what do. And I know he'll be back.
-就跟他聊聊吧 -跟死人聊天？
- Why don't you talk to him? - I should just have a chat with a dead guy?
不然就每晚都玩猜字游戏
Either that or we're going to be playing a lot of charades around here.
不过不能再猜了
And you're already out of Godzilla movies.
很难说.
I don't know.
你怕什么？
What's to be afraid of?
他又不是坏人，他可疼你了
You act like he's a bad guy and you know he loved you.
或许他变了
Maybe he's changed.
如果你真的相信能再见到鲍勃叔叔.
Mike, if you really believe that you've seen Uncle Bob...
就问问他想要怎样
then you should ask him what he wants.
-就像你对待病人一样？ -是的
- You say stuff like this to your patients? - Yes.
这个也要收费？
And they give you money for this?
我信不信鬼不重要
It doesn't matter what I believe, Mike.
重要的是你的脑子跟你开了个玩笑
What matters is that even if your mind played a trick on you...
空穴来风，事出有因
it did it for a reason.
寻找答案的最好方法是询问
And the best way of discovering that reason is to ask.
-问鲍勃叔叔 -问你心里面的他
- Uncle Bob. - Or your image of him.
懂吗？
You understand?
写信问可以吗？
I couldn't just do this by mail?
可以，有地址就行了
Yeah, if you have the address.
好，我来了
Okay. I'm going to do it.
我要走进去，勇者无惧
I'm gonna go in there, I'm gonna face my fear.
男子汉大丈夫，男子汉大丈夫
I'm gonna be a man. I'm gonna be a man.
男子汉大丈夫.
I'm gonna be a man. I'm gonna be a...
明天再做
Starting tomorrow.
勇敢，勇敢，勇敢.
Be a man. Be a man. Be a man. Be a man.
到厨房了
I'm in the kitchen.
到冰箱了
I'm at the refrigerator.
牛奶拿出来了
I'm taking out the buttermilk.
只是做梦，不是真的
It was a dream. It didn't really happen.
世上并没有鬼
There's no such thing as ghosts.
我是个男子汉，勇敢面对 鬼魂消失了
I was a man. I faced it and it went away.
再也见不到鲍勃叔叔了
I'll never see Uncle Bob again.
早上好
Morning, Mike.
妈妈
Mommy.
男子汉!做个男子汉
No, Mike. Be a man. You're gonna be a man.
-鲍勃叔叔？ -还好吧？
- Uncle Bob? - What's up, Mike?
还好，你继续
Nothing. Carry on.
记得上次吗？赌10块我会赢你
What about that limbo contest? $10 still says I can beat you, huh?
-你到底想要什么？ -想要什么？
- Look, what do you want from me? - What do I want from you?
想要你的10块钱
I want your $10, right?
我可以给你20，要什么都可以
Look, you can have $20. I don't care. Anything you want.
-别缠着我! -缠着你？
- Just quit haunting me! - Haunting you?
只是玩玩，别紧张
I was just kidding you, Mike. Try to lighten up.
别碰我
Look, don't touch me.
麦克，别误会
Mike, don't take this wrong...
-你怎么怪怪的？ -我怪怪的？
- but you're acting a little strange. - I'm acting strange?
你已经死了，还在厨房跑了10公里？
Look, you're running a 10K in my kitchen and you're dead.
10公里？
10K?
-我什么？ -我感到很遗憾，我说你死了
- I'm what? - I'm sorry to have to be the one to tell you.
我听到更遗憾
Not half as sorry as I am to hear it.
你肯定我死了？
You're sure about this?
对，星期五参加你的葬礼了
Yeah, I'm positive. I went to your funeral on Friday.
葬礼隆重吗？
Good funeral?
很隆重，许多人来了 爸爸哭了
Yeah, good funeral. Lot of people came. Dad cried.
杰森这好家伙
Good old Jason, huh?
杰克.霍拉德有没有来？
Did Jack Hollard show up?
他老说自己会先走一步.
He always said he was going to belly-up before...
怎么了？我没死!我还活着!
What am I saying? What am I saying? I'm not dead! I'm alive!
差点被你骗了
You had me going for a minute.
他还没听懂我的话
I can see I'm not getting my point across here.
鲍勃叔叔 上个星期你都做些什么了？
Look, Uncle Bob, what have you been doing for the last week?
记不清了，像往常一样
I don't know. The usual stuff, I guess.
-例如呢？ -例如跑步.
- Like what? - Like running and...
-有别人说话吗？ -有
- Have you talked to anybody? - Yeah.
-谁？ -当然是你
- Who? - You, of course.
还有谁？
Who else?
这就怪了.
You know, that's crazy, but...
这个星期只记得跟你说过话
I can't remember talking to anyone else this week but you.
-还记得什么？ -都在跑步
- What do you remember? - Running, mostly.
这星期跑步状态真好
Boy, I had some good runs this week.
鲍勃叔叔，一个星期都在跑步.
Uncle Bob, don't you think it's a little weird...
你不觉得有点怪吗？
to spend a whole week doing nothing but running?
是有点怪
Yeah, that is weird, huh?
很怪
Real weird.
为什么我还没意识到呢？
I just don't know why I didn't see it before.
我死了
I'm dead.
这样就简单多了
Seems simple enough now, huh?
麦克，谢谢你
I want to thank you, Michael.
不客气
Hey, don't mention it.
这种事情你自个儿知道就好
It was just something I thought you should know.
我要走了
I have to go now.
-现在就走？ -是的
- What, right now? - Yeah.
-鲍勃叔叔，等等 -我早该走了
- Uncle Bob, wait. - Way past my time.
-等等 -什么事？
- Wait, Uncle Bob. - Yes, Michael?
你要去哪？就这么抛开一切？
Where are you going? You just can't leave me here like this.
别担心，麦克，没事的
Don't worry, Michael. It's all right. Really.
不，我再也不能见到你了
No, it's not. I mean, I'm never going to see you again!
你要走了，留也留不住
You're leaving me, there's not a thing I can do about it, right?
-可以留 -什么？
- Sure there is. - What?
留在心里
Remember me.
-什么？ -留在心里
- What? - Remember me.
还记得你妈妈那次做寿司.
Remember the time your mom made sushi...
我们都穿上日本服吗？
and we all dressed up in Japanese costume?
记得，你却打扮成哥斯拉
Yeah, and you came as Godzilla.
我知道这是你最崇拜的明星
I knew it was your favorite movie star.
还记得我们讲过的笑话吗？
Remember all the corny jokes we used to tell, huh?
-刺猬亲热时怎样？ -战战兢兢
- How do two porcupines make love? - Very carefully.
还记得我死后你往我脸上涂剃须膏吗？
Remember the time I died in the den and you put whipped cream on my face?
可我不知道你死了
I didn't know you were dead.
等等，如果你死了.
Wait a minute, if you were dead...
你怎么知道剃须膏的事？
how did you know about the whipped cream?
我知道了许多不知道的事
I know a lot of things I didn't know before.
麦克，对不起 我总是开你玩笑，让你难看
Mike, I'm sorry I always teased you and tried to embarrass you.
没关系，屈辱能锻炼人格
That's okay. I mean, humiliation builds character.
这就对了
There you go then.
我是不会离开你的
You see, I'm not leaving you.
我会留在你的心中
I'm in your memory.
溶入你的人格里
I'm in your character.
我是你的一部分
I'm part of you.
麦克，再见
Goodbye, Mike.
鲍勃叔叔，再见
Goodbye, Uncle Bob.
我还是回去睡觉吧
I guess I'd better get to bed.
除非我其实正在睡觉
Unless I'm already up there.
麦克，早上好
Morning, Mike.
-昨晚睡得好吗？ -很好
- Did you sleep all right, last night? - Yeah, no problem.
-事情都解决了 -不害怕了？
- I worked the whole thing out. - No more fears?
硬汉又怎会害怕
No, not this cowboy.
-好，吃早餐吧 -好的
- Great. All right. See you at breakfast. - Okay.
麦克，拜托
Come on, Mike.
我说过多少次了，毛巾别到处扔
How many times do I have to tell you not to leave your towels lying around?
妈，这毛巾不是我的
Hey, Mom, this isn't my towel.
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.04.01